A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration Electronic Files, Email, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
- Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)., Extent: 37756 emails.
  - Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Files, Subseries C. Lynette Hammond Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
    Correspondents include: Mike Abbott, Jeffrey Anderson, Lynda Sharp Anderson, Alisa Bailey, Peter Blake, Mary Broz, Preston Bryant, Steve Calhoun, Marc Cheatham, Jackie Cunningham, Alex Daniel, Ray Davenport, Brian Davis, Jay DeBoer, Paula Dehetre, Suzette Denslow, Susan Dewey, Dave Dickson, Jerry Edwards, Bill Ernest, Dolores Esser, Joyce Fogg, Marc Follmer, Patrick Gottschalk, Steven Gould, Alleyn Harned, Victor Harrison, Ed Hegamyer, Conover Hunt, Gary Janak, Mike Kaestner, Tim Kaine, Nicholas Kessler, Harold Kretzer, Vivek Kundra, Daniel LeBlanc, Mike Lehmkuhler, Bill Leighty, Alfonso Lopez, Sam Lupica, Charles Massie, Robert McClintock, Gary McLaren, Sandi McNinch, Steven Mondul, Elizabeth Moran, Franklin Munyan, Bill Murray, Judy Napier, Jack Nelson, Aida Pacheco, Liz Povar, Barbara Reese, Gail Robinson, Shelby Robinson, Nikki Rovner, Mark Rubin, Bill Shelton, Brian Shepard, Rick Siger, Christine Simpson, Delacey Skinner, David Smith, David Spears, John Sternlicht, Marilyn Tavenner, Lynda Tran, Wayne Turnage, Aaron Ver, Coleman Walsh, Stephen Walz, Bo Willis, Ann Wright, and Richard Zorn.
  - Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, Subseries D. David N. Smith Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
    This subseries contains 352 emails in two PST files: DNSMITH.PST and KaineLibdnsmith.pst. David N. Smith served as Deputy Secretary of Commerce and Trade from January 2006 to January 2010. Smith was secretariat liaison to the Department of Business Assistance, Department of Housing and Community Development, Board of Accountancy, Virginia Employment Commission, Virginia Housing Development Authority, and Virginia Resource Authority. Prior to his appointment, Smith served as Vice President of Commercial Lending at Consolidated Bank and Trust.
    - DNSMITH.PST, 2009-2010.
      DNSMITH.PST contains five emails sent and received by David N. Smith between September 2009 and January 2010.
    - KaineLibdnsmith.pst, 2006-2009.
      KaineLibdnsmith.pst contains 347 emails sent and received by David N. Smith between January 2006 and December 2009. There are eight privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to records containing personal information.
      Subjects include: urban policy and Foreclosure Task Force.
      Correspondents include: Lynda Sharp Anderson, Sheryl Bailey, Marc Cheatham, Dolores Esser, Patrick Gottschalk, Earl McClenney, Wayne Turnage, and Stephen Walz.
  - Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, Subseries E. Vivek Kundra Email, 2006-2007.
    This subseries contains 555 emails in one PST file: VKUNDRA.PST. Vivek Kundra served as Assistant to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade from January 2006 to May 2007. In September 2006, Governor Kaine tasked Kundra to oversee the creation of the Business One-Stop website. Vivek left the administration in May 2007 when Mayor Adrian Fenty appointed him Chief Technology Officer for the District of Columbia.
    Prior to the Kaine administration, Kundra was the CEO of Creostar, a company focused on cyber security and information warfare.
    VKUNDRA.PST contains 555 emails sent and received by Vivek Kundra between January 2006 and August 2007.
    Subjects include: Business One Stop; legislation; urban policy; Economic Development Strategic Plan; India trade mission; broadband; and Small, Women-owned, and Minority-owned Business (SWAM) dashboard.
    Correspondents include: Aneesh Chopra, Patrick Gottschalk, Shea Hollifield, Bill Leighty, Judy Napier, Rick Siger, and David Smith.
  - Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, Subseries F. Alleyn Harned Email, 2006-2009.
    This subseries contains 5199 emails in two PST files: AHARNED.PST and KaineLibAHarned.pst. Alleyn Harned served as Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Trade from May 2007 to December 2009. From January 2006 to May 2007, Harned served as Special Assistant to the Secretary of Transportation (see Series IX. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, Subseries F. Alleyn Harned Email, 2006-2007).
    - AHARNED.PST, 2009.
      AHARNED.PST contains 130 emails sent and received by Alleyn Harned between May 2009 and December 2009.
      Subjects include: Virginia Israel Advisory Board.
      Correspondents include: Patrick Gottschalk, Lynnette Hammond, and David Smith.
    - KaineLibAHarned.pst, 2006-2009.
      KaineLibAHarned.pst contains 5069 emails sent and received by Alleyn Harned between May 2006 and December 2009. There are seven privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to records containing attorney-client communications and Virginia unemployment cases.
      Subjects include: Air Force Cyber Command (AFCYBER); state budget; Business One Stop; Governor's Commission on Climate Change; Department of Business Assistant (DBA) Consolidation study group; weekly reports from Commerce and Trade agencies; economic development projects (Rolls Royce, Greentech Automotive, CGI and SIR International); proposal by the United States Navy to move a nuclear-powered aircraft carrier from Norfolk Naval Station to Naval Station Mayport, Florida; Outlying Landing Field (OLF); Virginia Commercial Space Flight Authority; federal H-2B visa program; and Transportation Partnership Opportunity Fund (TPOF).
      Correspondents include: Jeffrey Anderson, Lynda Sharp Anderson, Alisa Bailey, Bennett Blodgett, Preston Bryant, Kim Busch, Hollie Cammarasana, Marc Cheatham, Aneesh Chopra, Alex Daniel, Dave Dickson, Jerry Edwards, Kim Ellett, Dolores Esser, Catherine Evans, Cathy Ghidotti, Melinda Glazer, Patrick Gottschalk, Lynette Hammond, Pierce Homer, Amanda Howe, Mike Kaestner, Elizabeth Kersey, Mike Lehmkuhler, Alfonso Lopez, Charles Massie, Robert McClintock, Christie Miller, Laurie Naismith, Judy Napier, Keith Oing, Tristen Pegram, Liz Povar, Billie Reed, Rick Richardson, Ralph Robbins, Frank Roberts, Stan Scott, Bill Shelton, Brian Shepard, Delacey Skinner, David Smith, Tamra Talmadge-Anderson, Lynda Tran, Wayne Turnage, William Vehrs, Wayne Waldrop, Stephen Walz, and Suzanne West.
  - Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, Subseries G. Stephen Walz Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
    This subseries contains 534 emails in two PST files: kaine archive.pst and SWALZ.PST. Stephen Walz served as Senior Advisor to the Governor for Energy Policy from 2007 to 2010. Walz directed the formulation of the Virginia Energy Plan. Walz was Director of Administration for the Department of Mines, Minerals and Energy and was loaned to the administration.
    Kaine archive.pst contains 534 emails sent and received by Stephen Walz between July 2006 and December 2009. The majority of email is from members of the public commenting on the work of the Governor's Commission on Climate Change. SWALTZ.PST contains one email from January 2010.
  - Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, Subseries H. Catherine Evans Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
    This subseries contains 3747 emails in one PST file: KaineLibcevans.pst. Catherine Evans served as Executive Assistant to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade from January 2006 to January 2010.
    KaineLibcevans.pst contains 3747 emails sent and received by Catherine Evans between January 2006 and January 2010. There are 21 privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to records containing attorney-client communications and Virginia unemployment cases.
    Subjects include: The bulk of the email consists of agency response to constituent correspondence, information on events attended by Secretary Gottschalk (agendas, minutes and background material), state budget, and drafts of Secretary Gottschalk's correspondence. On many of the emails, Evans was cc'd.
    Correspondents include: Jeffrey Anderson, Alisa Bailey, Joan Baker, Preston Bryant, Evie Christopher, Alex Daniel, Dave Dickson, Kim Ellett, Winston Evans, Marc Follmer, Cathy Ghidotti, Patrick Gottschalk, Lynette Hammond, Alleyn Harned, Vivek Kundra, Mike Lehmkuhler, Evelyn Lewis, Leslie McAlexander, Sandi McNinch, Jack Nelson, Liz Povar, Rick Richardson, Bill Shelton, Rick Siger, Christine Simpson, David Smith, Crystal Vincent, and Stephen Walz.
  - Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, Subseries I. Darryl Holt Email, 2008-2010 (bulk 2008-2009).
    This subseries contains 133 emails in one PST file: DHOLT.PST. Darryl Holt served as a Special Assistant from 2008 to 2010.
    DHOLT.PST contains 133 emails sent and received by Darryl Holt between February 2008 and January 2010. There are nine privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to records containing Virginia unemployment cases information.
    Subjects include: The majority of the email consists of constituent correspondence.
  - Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, Subseries J. Mike Coleman Email, 2009-2010 (bulk 2009).
    This subseries contains 181 emails in one PST file: KaineLibmcoleman.pst. Mike Coleman served as Base Realignment and Closure Commission (BRAC) Coordinator from 2009 to 2010.
    KaineLibmcoleman.pst contains 181 emails sent and received by Mike Coleman between September 2009 and January 2010.
    Subjects include: The majority of email consists of updating the Governor-elect Robert McDonnell's transition team on Base Realignment and Closure Commission (BRAC) issues.
    Correspondents include: Dave Dickson, Frank Roberts, and Terrie Suit.
- Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, 2005-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)., Extent: 13394 emails.
  The Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files series documents the electronic communication of the office during the Kaine administration. This series contains 13394 emails in eleven (11) subseries. Subseries have been designated for: A. Robert P. Crouch, Jr. Email, B. Steven Mondul Email, C. Wendy Hoffman Email, D. Susan Mongold Email, E. Mike McAllister Email, F. Constance McGeorge Email, G. Melissa McMenemy Email, H. Curtis Brown Email, I. Kerry Stuver Email, J. Megan Samford Email, and K. Jonathan Kiser Email. The email of Marc Follmer, Deputy Assistant for Commonwealth Preparedness and Senior Advisor to the Governor, can be found in Series I. Executive Office Email, Subseries H. There are no email files for Chris Essid, Commonwealth Interoperability Coordinator. There are 250 protected and confidential emails that are restricted from public access per Code of Virginia, 42-1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to: attorney-client communications, security information and continuity of government information.
  The Office of Commonwealth Preparedness collaborated with federal, state, and local officials as well as the private sector to develop a coordinated security and preparedness strategy and implementation plan. The office served as the liaison between the governor and the federal Department of Homeland Security. The duties of the office during the Kaine administration included the oversight, coordination and review of all disaster, emergency management, and terrorism management plans for the state and its agencies; served as the governor's representative on regional efforts to develop a coordinated security and preparedness strategy; served as a direct liaison between the governor's office and local governments and first responders; and educated the public on security and preparedness issues. The office also participated in several oversight groups that provided policy and guidance to the rest of the state. These groups included the Secure Commonwealth Panel, Commonwealth Preparedness Working Group (CPWG), Regional Preparedness Advisory Committees, and the Virginia Military Advisory Council. The Commonwealth Interoperability Coordinator's Office (CICO), reported directly to the Assistant for Commonwealth Preparedness and served as a direct liaison between the governor and Virginia's local governments and first responders on issues of emergency preparedness.
  Some of the major initiatives of the office during the administration of Governor Timothy Kaine were the National Capital Region (NCR), critical infrastructure protection, and the Virginia Higher Education Preparedness Consortium.
  - Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, Subseries A. Robert P. Crouch, Jr. Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
    This subseries contains 6329 emails in two PST files: KaineLibrcrouch.pst and RCROUCH.PST. Robert P. Crouch, Jr. served as Assistant to the Governor for Commonwealth Preparedness from January 2006 to January 2010. Crouch served as United States Attorney, Western District of Virginia from 1993 to 2001. During the administration of Governor Mark Warner, Crouch held two positions: Deputy Secretary of Public Safety from January 2002 to May 2005 and Legal Counselor to the Governor from May 2005 to January 2006.
    - KaineLibrcrouch.pst, 2006-2010.
      KaineLibrcrouch.pst contains 6329 emails sent and received by Robert P. Crouch, Jr. between January 2006 and January 2010. There are 219 privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to records containing attorney-client communications.
      Subjects include: 16 April 2007 shooting at Virginia Tech; weekly reports; Fort Monroe; creation of the State Interoperability Executive Committee (SIEC) by Executive Order 30 (2006); Secure Commonwealth Panel; creation and leadership of multi-agency Evacuation and Sheltering Task Force; hurricane preparedness; National Capital Region (NCR) including meetings of the Senior Policy Group (SPG); Commonwealth Higher Education Preparedness Consortium; campus security conference (2007); Outlying Landing Field (OLF); Air Force Cyber Command (AFCYBER); Base Realignment and Closure Commission (BRAC); Governor's Motorcycle Advisory Council; Office of Commonwealth Preparedness legislation; budget issues; Naval Air Station Oceana in Virginia Beach; and a proposal by the United States Navy to move a nuclear-powered aircraft carrier from Norfolk Naval Station to Naval Station Mayport, Florida.
      Correspondents include: Mark Anthony, Mark Boyer, Curtis Brown, Preston Bryant, Janet Clements, Darrell Darnell, Marla Decker, Dave Dickson, Chris Essid, Kevin Fanroy, Marc Follmer, Christopher Geldart, Kevin Hall, Wendy Hoffman, Pierce Homer, Catherina Hutchins, Tim Kaine, Coyner Kelley, Steve Kral, Andy Lauland, Bill Leighty, Les Lilley, Thomas Lockwood, Alfonso Lopez, Sue Mahon, John Marshall, Robert Mauskapf, Steve Mondul, Susan Mongold, Eric Murdock, Edward Reiskin, Frank Roberts, Larry Roberts, Mark Rubin, Felix Sarfo-Kantanka, Brian Shepard, Rick Siger, Delacey Skinner, Bob Spieldenner, Marilyn Tavenner, and Wayne Turnage.
    - RCROUCH.PST, 2009-2010.
      RCROUCH.PST contains 23 emails sent and received by Robert P. Crouch, Jr. between December 2009 and January 2010.
      Subjects include: transition to the Governor Robert McDonnell administration.
      Correspondents include: Janet Clements and Terry Suit.
  - Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, Subseries B. Steven Mondul Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
    This subseries contains 3864 emails in two PST files: KaineLibsmondul.pst and SMONDUL.PST. Steven Mondul served as Deputy Assistant to the Governor for Commonwealth Preparedness from January 2006 to January 2010. Mondul's primary area of responsibilities were emergency management, security, strategic planning, critical infrastructure protection, grants and military affairs.
    - KaineLibsmondul.pst, 2006-2009.
      KaineLibsmondul.pst contains 3820 emails sent and received by Steven Mondul between January 2006 and December 2009. There are 18 privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to records containing attorney-client communications and security information.
      Subjects include: 16 April 2007 shooting at Virginia Tech; Outlying Landing Field (OLF); Commonwealth Preparedness Working Group (CPWG); proposal by the United States Navy to move a nuclear-powered aircraft carrier from Norfolk Naval Station to Naval Station Mayport, Florida; budget issues; preparations for the 20 January 2009 presidential inauguration; hurricane preparedness including Hurricane Evacuation and Sheltering Task Force; Naval Air Station Oceana in Virginia Beach; aerial photography of military bases in Virginia; State Interoperability Executive Committee (SIEC); First Responder Authentication Credentials (FRAC); Jamestown 2007 commemoration; and REAL ID.
      Correspondents include: Cheryl Adkins, Mark Anthony, Stewart Baker, Curtis Brown, Richard Catoire, Janet Clements, Michael Cline, Perry Cogburn, Robert Crouch, Edward Edens, David Ekern, Chris Essid, Marc Follmer, Wendy Hoffman, Jim Keck, Alfonso Lopez, Mike McAllister, Constance McGeorge, Susan Mongold, Frank Roberts, Brian Shepard, Delacey Skinner, and Wayne Turnage.
    - SMONDUL.PST, 2009-2010.
      SMONDUL.PST contains 34 emails sent and received by Steven Mondul from January 2009 to January 2010.
      Subjects include: Bowers Hill Evacuation Project.
      Correspondents include: Robert Crouch.
  - Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, Subseries C. Wendy Hoffman Email, 2006-2009.
    This subseries contains 2076 emails in one PST file: KaineLibWHoffman.pst. Wendy Hoffman served as Executive Assistant from January 2006 to January 2010. She was responsible for the administration of the Office of Commonwealth Preparedness.
    KaineLibWHoffman.pst contains 2076 emails sent and received by Wendy Hoffman between January 2006 and December 2009. There are eight privacy protected and confidential emails in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to records containing attorney-client communications and continuity of government information.
    Subjects include: weekly reports from Office of Commonwealth Preparedness staff; Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority (FMFADA); campus security conference (2007); and Commonwealth Preparedness Working Group (CPWG).
    Correspondents include: Joan Baker, Curtis Brown, Robert Crouch, Chris Essid, Marc Follmer, Mike McAllister, Constance McGeorge, Melissa McMenemy, Steve Mondul, Susan Mongold, Megan Samford, Kerry Stuver, and Davis Walsh.
  - Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, Subseries D. Susan Mongold Email, 2006-2008.
    This subseries contains 191 emails in one PST file: KaineLibsmongold.pst. Susan Mongold served as State Grants Coordinator from 2006 to December 2008. Mongold coordinated the federal grant process and assisted with strategic planning.
    KaineLibsmongold.pst contains 191 emails sent and received by Susan Mongold between October 2006 and November 2008. There are two attorney-client communications in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78.
    Subjects include: federal grants and State Preparedness Report.
    Correspondents include: Cheryl Adkins, Robert Crouch, Wendy Hoffman, and Steven Mondul.
  - Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, Subseries E. Mike McAllister Email, 2009-2010 (bulk 2009).
    This subseries contains 175 emails in one PST file: MMCALLISTER.PST. Mike McAllister served as Critical Infrastructure Protection Coordinator from 2008 to January 2010. McAllister coordinated all critical infrastructure matters, security, personal surety, and credentialing.
    MMCALLISTER.PST contains 175 emails sent and received by Mike McAllister between March 2009 and January 2010. There is one email with security information in this PST file that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78.
    Subjects include: critical infrastructure and security clearances.
    Correspondents include: Robert Crouch, Steven Mondul, Megan Samford, and W. Duane Stafford.
  - Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, Subseries F. Constance McGeorge Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
    This subseries contains 39 emails in one PST file: CMCGEORGE.PST. Constance McGeorge served as a Special Assistant to the Governor from January 2006 to December 2007 and Commonwealth Interoperability Coordinator from January 2008 to January 2010.
    CMCGEORGE.PST contains 39 emails sent and received by Constance McGeorge between January 2006 and January 2010.
    Subjects include: State Interoperability Executive Committee (SIEC).
  - Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, Subseries G. Melissa McMenemy Email, 2005-2006.
    This subseries contains 488 emails in one PST file: mmcmenemy.pst. Melissa McMenemy served as Assistant to Commonwealth Interoperability Coordinator from 2005 to November 2006.
    Mmcmenemy.pst contains 488 emails sent and received by Melissa McMenemy between October 2005 and November 2006. There is one security related email in this PST file that is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78.
    Subjects include: interoperability/Commonwealth Interoperability Coordinator's Office (CICO); State Interoperability Executive Committee (SIEC); and weekly reports.
    Correspondents include: Erin Elder, Chris Essid, Wendy Hoffman, Steven Mondul, and Ami Retamoza.
  - Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, Subseries H. Curtis Brown Email, 2006-2009.
    This subseries contains 80 emails in one PST file: KaineLibcbrown.pst. Curtis Brown served as Senior Special Assistant to the Governor from 2006 to January 2010. Brown was responsible for the coordination of higher education preparedness, state government continuity of operations plans (COOP), continuity of government (COG), and served on the Capitol Square Security Working Group.
    KaineLibcbrown.pst contains 80 emails sent and received by Curtis Brown between April 2006 and December 2009.
    Subjects include: campus security conference (2007) and continuity of government (COG).
    Correspondents include: Robert Crouch, Steven Mondul, and Rueyenne White.
  - Series XVI. Office of Commonwealth Preparedness Electronic Files, Subseries I. Kerry Stuver Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
    This subseries contains 22 emails in two PST files: KLUGAR.PST and KaineLibklugar.pst. Kerry Stuver served as Special Assistant for Interoperability from 2006 to January 2010. Stuver provided administrative support to the interoperability program.